VLATKO EFREMOVSKI

iOS Developer



vlatko.efremovski@gmail.com



in <u>vlatko-efremovski</u>



github.com/Svegjan



2282749/vlatko-svegjan



Naturally curious iOS developer with over 9 years of experience, having spent most of my time working at various companies and as an independent contractor. I have worked on a variety of projects, including E-Commerce, CRM, SAAS apps using Bluetooth tech, Enterprise apps, News/Marketing apps, and more.

For more details regarding my work experience, please view my portfolio

Recent History

Lead Mobile Developer

The List

March 2022 - Present

Decreased churn rate of the Consumer app by 20% after implementing tracking metrics and setting up targeted campaigns.

Managed the development and release of the Seller App, by closely collaborating with stakeholders and merchants.

Improved communication lines between departments.

Lead iOS Developer

Upsales Nordic AB March 2018 - March 2022

> Spearheaded a major restructuring of the legacy CRM app and developed a brand new, improved and more scalable version of the app in Swift; increased user engagement - while leading a team of developers, utilizing an agile workflow.

Communicated with different clients to develop custom white-label versions of the app.

Co-founder & Mobile Developer

Enspyra Tech April 2016 - March 2018

> Managed a cross-functional team, ranging from mobile developers, digital marketers, content writers and collaborated with business development and data analysis operations.

> Led a mobile team in the development of News & Marketing Apps, improving the stability and scalability of the applications, prompting the increase of the user base.

Education

Msc in Management of Information Systems

University American College Skopje 2012 - 2015

Thesis: "Implementation of Monetization Practices in Mobile Applications"

BSc in Software Engineering

University American College Skopje 2009 - 2012

Developed a system for a virtual medical office using ASP.NET technology together with SQL server 2008 as a graduation thesis.



Swift

Writing Swift full-time for 7+ years and closely following its evolution since 1.0. I follow the latest trends and keep up with the development of the iOS ecosystem, and, as of late, this includes the ever-so improving framework of SwiftUI.

Objective C

Prior to Swift, I was introduced to mobile development with Objective-C, with which I developed and worked on a multitude of different apps.

Communicating ideas

I have a special talent for breaking down complex topics and presenting them in an easy to understand manner.

I get immense fulfillment from mentoring and knowledge sharing.

Other Skills

Mentoring and Managing UIKit, CallKit, SwiftUI CocoaPods / Carthage / SPM Agile and SCRUM methodologies Continuous Integration - CircleCI Jenkins, Bitrise

MVC, MVP, MVVM Combine, React-Native **Emotional Intelligence XCode** Git version control, Jira AdobeXD, Figma

A Interests

Football Crypto Travel Jogging Hiking Blockchain **LOTR** Books

Languages

Macedonian, English, Swedish Native or bilingual proficiency